ISAAC MILLS-OWOO

Newark, DE | ikejrmillsowoo@gmail.com | https://github.com/lkejrmillsowoo | www.linkedin.com/in/isaac-mills-owoo

Professional Summary

Highly skilled IT Student, Supervisor, and previous Registered Respiratory Therapist with over 10 years of experience in training, onboarding, and educating staff, looking to transition to a Junior Software Developer. Shifting focus and learning new skills in the Information Technology field, including completing a Master's in Information Systems and a Full-Stack Web Development Boot Camp.

Skills

- Building front end Applications from Start to Finish
- Responsive & User-Centric Design
- Optimizing Data Storage for Static Content
- Project Scope, Scheduling & Management
- Structuring Code & Data

- Risk & Quality Management
- Managing & Mentoring Employees
- Problem-Solving & Collaboration Skills
- Attention to Detail & Ensuring Accuracy
- Excellent Verbal & Written Communication

Education

Wilmington University

Master of Science in Information Systems Technologies & Internet/Web Design

- Gained skills to manage complex systems and coordination relationships between business requirements and solutions.
- Explored web design with JavaScript, HTML, Visual Basic, as well as advanced multimedia and animation.
- Enhanced abilities to oversee Development and Implementation teams, and lead projects from inception to completion.
- Applied models for planning, organizing, designing, managing, and implementing IS within modern organizations.
- Successfully learned to manage risks related to use, processes, storage, and transmission of information and data.
- Assessed ethical practices in implementing IA policy, standards, and regulation, and systematic interrelationships.
- Focused on the use of software tools to create compelling web designs, and learned syntax of the scripting language.
- Covered developing and displaying information on the web by writing HTML, with an overview of XML.
- Learned to design and develop database-driven websites, concentrating on viz to produce an e-commerce site.
- Addressed opportunities to interject aesthetics and design principles into e-business systems to drive customer loyalty.
- Developed skills to build security policy and SOP for implementing new networks and web infrastructures.

Wilmington University - 2020

Master of Business Administration in Management Information Systems

- Covered project, change, and data management and analysis, along with modeling, design, data comms, and networking.
- Developed a deep understanding of informational practices for business, education, and Government organizations.
- Built qualitative/quantitative critical thinking skills related to the development of sound business tactics and strategy.
- Effectively learned to prepare and implement strategic plans that include creative, feasible business alternatives.
- Addressed techniques for managing corporate data resources and the design and development of large database systems.
- Examined data distribution, administration, warehousing, cleansing, and mining, as well as concurrent processing.
- Learned systems development life cycle, analysis, and design techniques along with IS systems planning methods.
- Explored project identification and selection, requirements collection and structuring, as well as interface design.
- Expertly and efficiently utilized tools including rapid application development, prototyping, and visual development.
- Covered telecommunications fundamentals including data, image, voice, and video, as well as architecture and protocol.
- Studied standards and security for design, implementation, and management of digital networks, and LAN and WAN.
- Examined e-commerce and associated web sites and practices, and middleware for wireless systems and multimedia.

- Covered project initiation, planning, integration, scope, time, cost, quality control, risk management, and reporting.
- Learned to manage change resulting from the introduction or revision of IS, including training and documentation.
- Gained skills in aligning competitive strategy and IS, as well as developing policies to achieve organizational goals.

Wilmington University, New Castle, DE – 2011

Bachelor of Science in Allied Health Education

Delaware Technical & Community College, Newark, DE - 2009

Associate of Science in Respiratory Therapy

Technical Certifications

AWS Cloud Practitioner Certification – Amazon Web Services

- Gained an understanding of the AWS Cloud, the value of cloud computing and AWS, and making the infrastructure scalable.
- Utilized methods and tools to maintain security and protect data, while identifying deployment and management options.
- Defined basic global infrastructure and understood key services and use cases, including computing and analytics.
- Addressed account management, pricing models, and core characteristics of deploying and operating in the AWS Cloud.
- Effectively learned to make decisions based on architectural principles while identifying and solving configuration issues.
- Designed architectures to decouple infrastructure and reduce interdependencies, and automated resource deployment.

HTML; CSS; JavaScript; React; Git - CodeAcademy

- Addressed multiple versatile, robust programming languages to examine front- and back-end web development.
- Learned basic object-oriented concepts using the latest JavaScript syntax, while learning programming fundamentals.
- Gained the skills to ensure websites remain legible and visually appealing across a variety of devices and platforms.
- Utilized responsive design techniques to increase website accessibility to reach a much larger audience of users.
- Understood ways to create visualizations, make informed decisions, and predict events through Machine Learning.

HTML; CSS; JavaScript/jQuery; Bootstrap; React; React Native; Node.js; Git; GitHub – NuCamp Coding BC – 06/2021

- Learned to build websites that can be developed for all screen sizes, including addressing responsive design and grids.
- Explored React, the #1 JavaScript library, and covered advanced aspects of JavaScript ES6 and React components.
- Updated and packaged a responsive website built using Bootstrap and React, publishing as a true mobile application.
- Utilized React Native and Expo SDK to access all native hardware capabilities of modern phones and tablets.
- Joined teams and contributed to projects, leveraging the version control system Git to track all changes being made.

Technical Skills

HTML

CSS

JavaScript/jQuery

Bootstrap

React

React Native

• Node.js

• Git

• GitHub

Command Line

• MS Office Suite

EMAR

Learning Management Systems

Professional Experience

Supervisor, Epic EMAR Transition Manager & Registered Respiratory Therapist – Good Shepherd Penn Partners – 2013 to Present Respiratory Therapist – Jennersville Regional Hospital – 2017 to Present

Registered Respiratory Care Manager – Nemours Children's Hospital – 2010 to 2019

Registered Respiratory Therapist – Select Specialty Hospitals – 2011 to 2017

Medical Certifications & Licensure

- BLS
- Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS) Certification 2010 to Present
- Registered Respiratory Therapist, License #YM01293 State of PA 12/2022
- Registered Respiratory Therapist State of DE 11/2022

Professional Affiliations & Activities

Member - American Association of Respiratory Care - 2009 to Present

Member - Delaware Association of Respiratory Care - 2009 to Present

Member - Delaware Association of Respiratory Care - 2011 to Present

Member – National Board of Respiratory Care – 2009 to Present